

Jasbinder Kaur Reservation Executive

Mobile: +91 8882696475, +91 7982551966

Mail: jasbinderk3@gmai.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jasbinder-kaur-grover-670303a5/

SUMMARY

I am a qualified and professional with a high level of experience and a real zest for sharing my passion to serve the guests. I aim to attain an engaging position in the field of hospitality management. I hope to create wow experiences for the guest at every moment with the positive mindset.

EDUCATION

2016-2018

Masters of Hospitality Management Institute of Hotel and Tourism Management Maharshi Dayanand University, Rohtak

2013-2016

Bachelors of Hospitality Management Institute of Hotel and Tourism Management Maharshi Dayanand University, Rohtak

2011 - 2013

CBSE, High Schooling Sarvodaya Vidyalaya Sharda Niketan, Delhi

CAREER

RESERVATION EXECUTIVE ALILA FORT BISHANGARH, JAIPUR FROM FFR 2021 TILL DATE

- Assist to make all room reservations and ensure maximize room revenue for all and ensure all reservation detail update on all computers within required operating procedures.
- Looking after the reservation department's operation and team management.
- Analyze all guest and travel agent requirements through telephone and emails and recommend suitable options for all customers and assist to confirm all reservations.
- Coordinate with sales department and manage all communication for group bookings and maintain all calendars for hotel and inform operation staff for same.

RESERVATION SUPERVISOR CROWNE PLAZA NEW DELHI, ROHINI FROM JUL 2019 TO JAN 2021

- Analyze all guest and travel agent requirements through telephone and emails and recommend suitable options for all customers and assist to confirm all reservations.
- Coordinate with sales department and manage all communication for group bookings and maintain all calendars for hotel and inform operation staff for same.
- Manage all incoming calls for reservation department and ensure response all queries and maintain professional relationship and atmosphere at all times.
- Develop and maintain professional relationships with all computer associate and supervise and inform manager of all issues and coordinate with call center to resolve same.
- Assist to book and block all rooms according to required standards and manage all special reservations and monitor all reservations and discounts.
- Manage all mails from guests and ensure response and completion of all guest requests and evaluate all reservation logbook and provide update on everyday basis.

RESERVATION SUPERVISOR THE LEELA AMBIENCE CONVENTION HOTEL, KARKARDOOMA FROM DEC 2018 TO JUL 2019

- Ensure all incoming calls with courtesy and ensure efficient resolution of all guest inquiries for various hotel services and operations.
- Processes reservations by mail, telephone, telex, cable, fax or central reservation systems
- Processes reservations from the sales office, other hotel departments, and travel agents.
- Creates and maintains reservation records by date of arrival and alphabetical listing.
- Processes cancellations and modifications and promptly relays this information to the front desk.
- Understands the hotel's policy on guaranteed reservation and no-shows.
- Processes advance deposits on reservations.

SENIOR FRONT OFFICE ASSOCIATE THE LEELA AMBIENCE CONVENTION HOTEL, KARKARDOOMA FROM OCT 2017 TO DEC 2018

- Welcome guests and visitors to the front lobby of the facility, record their information and choose a room or rooms for them based on their needs.
- Collect the guest's payment using either credit/debits cards, cash or checking account information for rooms at the end of each stay and ask for a room deposit when necessary.
- Settle the facility register at the end of each shift or day by counting the drawer, printing receipts and running financial activity reports.
- Communicate with other hotel staff, such as housekeeping or maintenance, when rooms are ready to be cleaned or repaired in preparation for a new guest.
- Answer phone switchboards and transfer calls and take messages.

FRONT OFFICE ASSOCIATE JAYPEE SIDDHARTH, RAJENDRA PLACE, DELHI FROM JUN 2016 TO OCT 2017

- Administer all guest departure on everyday basis and ensure compliance to all established manual and computer procedures.
- Develop and maintain effective professional relationship with all clients and provide assistance on phone and in person.
- Ensure optimal level of customer services for all guests and manage all communication

- with guests for check in and check out process.
- Maintain neat and clean desk and lobby area at all times and greet all guests with courtesy.
- Administer and perform all cashier functions and perform efficient cash drawer and ensure accuracy in calculating all credit card payments.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Job Training in Front Office Department The Gateway Resort, Damdama Lake DEC 2015 to MAR 2016
- Industrial Training- Major Departments Crowne Plaza New Delhi, Rohini MAY 2014 to OCT 2014

SPECIALIZATION: Guest Lecturer of Tourism Management in secondary schools

SKILLS

Communication

> Team Work

Emotional Intelligence

Attention To Detail

Multitasking

Quick Learner

Good System's Knowledge

Hardworking

PERSONAL INFO

Father's Name: Mr Mahender Singh

Date of Birth: 12th Dec 1995

Height: 152.04 cm

Weight: 58 kg
Marital Status: Single

Permanent Address: WZ- 3258 Mahindra Park Rani Bagh, Delhi

Declaration:

I hereby declare that all the information contained in this resume is in accordance with facts or truths to my knowledge. I take full responsibility for the correctness of the said information.

Jasbinder Kaur

Signature:

Date: